Mommy loves you to death.
Evil Dead Rise is a horror, thriller film directed by Lee Cronin.
A reunion between two estranged sisters gets cut short by the rise of flesh-possessing demons, thrusting them
into a primal battle for survival as they face the most nightmarish version of family imaginable.
Beth, played by Lily Sullivan.
Ellie, played by Alyssa Sutherland.
Danny, played by Morgan Davies.
Bridget, played by Gabrielle Echols.
Kassie, played by Nell Fisher.
Mr. Fonda, played by Mark Mitchinson.
Evil Dead Rise is a 2023 American supernatural horror
film written and directed by Lee Cronin.
The film stars Lily Sullivan and Alyssa Sutherland as two estranged
sisters trying to survive and save their family from Deadites.
Morgan Davies, Gabrielle Echols, and Nell Fisher (in her
film debut) appear in supporting roles.
The film's development was preceded by scrapped plans for direct sequels to Evil Dead (2013) and
Army of Darkness (1992), and a fourth season of Ash vs Evil Dead (2015–2018).
By October 2019, Sam Raimi announced that a new film was in development, with Rob Tapert producing,
Raimi and Bruce Campbell executive producing, and Cronin writing and directing the project.
New Line Cinema (the first film's distributor) was
announced as a production company involved.
Principal photography took place in New Zealand from June to October 2021.
The film was originally set to premiere on the streaming
service HBO Max, but distributor Warner Bros.
Pictures opted to release the film theatrically
first after positive test screenings.
Evil Dead Rise had its world premiere at South by Southwest on March 15, 2023, and was
theatrically released in the United States on April 21, 2023, by Warner Bros.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed $147 million
worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of the series.
At the 51st Saturn Awards, it earned two nominations:
Best Horror Film and Best Make-up.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
pregnancy, earthquake, gore, sequel.
The tone is dark and intense.